<u>Yogesh M Gadhia</u> Mobile: +91- 9630693788

Date of Birth: 01-02-1962 email: ygadhia@gmail.com

Permanent Address:

3A, Shardakunj Society, Near New Vikas Gruh Road,

Paldi-Ahmedabad-380007

M No: - 9630693788

Core Competencies:

Experience in Multiple Development Projects of Government, Non-Government and Private Sector Organizations; Education, Livelihoods, Health, Natural Resource Management, Swashakti Project, Women and Livelihood Restoration project, Vanbadhu yojna etc

- Programme's overall financial and physical monitoring and reporting.
- Team Management
- Administrative work
- Reporting/Documentation
- Coordination/Networking

Employment Record

Accounts Head: - Tata Institute of Social Science, Mumbai in School of Vocation Education, Mumbai from July-2023

- Handle Accounts
- Preparation and submission of fund utilization statements to various funding agencies
- Training of staff on account keeping and finance management.
- Related work of staff recruitment appointment order etc.
- Check & Verify Invoices of purchases and take confirmation from concerned person or department for further action
- Statutory deduction from the bills/release of salary Via Income tax, Professional Tax, Provided funds, TDS from Contractor payment etc. as per the applicable law
- Timely submission of statutory documentation with Govt. Department.
- Monitoring of fund utilization

Accountant Cum Administrator with Indian Institute of Public Health -Gandhinagar from 21st August,2020 to 30th June,2023.

- Handle Accounts and Administrative work of the project
- Preparation and submission of fund utilization statements to various funding agencies

- Training of staff on account keeping and finance management.
- Related work of staff recruitment appointment order etc.
- Check & Verify Invoices of purchases and take confirmation from concerned person or department for further action
- Statutory deduction from the bills/release of salary Via Income tax, Professional Tax, Provided funds, TDS from Contractor payment etc. as per the applicable law
- Timely submission of statutory documentation with Govt. Department.
- Monitoring of fund utilization

Project Assistant with IPE Global from September,2019 to August,2020 at Bhopal-Madhya Pradesh

- Handle Accounts and Administrative work of the project
- Coordination with concerned department within the state and head office.
- Support and liaison work for various events such as Conferences/workshops.
- Support to the consultant for collection of various data from the department and liaison with various department.
- Report to the country office at New Delhi

Project Assistant, March 2014 to August 2019 UNDP/- Strengthening State Strategies for Climate Action, at Bhopal -Madhya Pradesh

- Handle Accounts and Administrative work of the project
- Coordination with concerned department within the state and head office.
- Support and liaison work for various events such as Conferences/workshops.
- · Report to the country office at New Delhi.
- Supporting State authority -EPCO in their accounting system pertaining various grant from Department of Science & Technology, supporting, and preparing budget, reporting etc.

Programme Manager (Administration and Finance), 2013-2014 Tata Institute of Social Sciences, Mumbai (Maharashtra); IDBI/Rural Transformation Project and NUSSD (National University Student Skill Development Programme)

- · Overall coordination and monitoring of NUSSD and IDBI Project
- Handling accounts and administrative work of the project including Fellows/interns accounts
- Hand-holding support to Interns/Fellows

Manager (Administration and Finance) - 2005 to 2013 Cohesion Foundation Trust-Ahmedabad (Gujarat)

- Implementation of the projects
- Planning, Monitoring and Evaluation of the programmes.
- Team Management- managing inter-relations of the staff.
- Documentation of different projects in terms of preparing different reports, success stories,

- Maintenance of Financial Management and Accounting Systems
- Coordination/Networking with different NGOs, Government agencies, Funding agencies and Private sector

Finance and Administration:

- Budgeting for the projects
- Monitoring of fund utilization
- Preparation and submission of fund utilization statements to various funding agencies like:
 OXFAM, CARE, CONCERN WORLDWIDE, Commissioner, Women and Child Development, on monthly basis
- Training of staff and SHG members on account keeping and finance management.
- Related work of staff recruitment appointment order- transfer order.
- Checking & Scrutinizing staff claim VIZ. Medical bills, Travel bills, Leave Travel Allowance, (LTA) etc as per the organization rules and procedures
- Check & Verify Invoices of purchases and take confirmation from concerned person or department for further action
- Statutory deduction from the bills/release of salary Via Income tax, Professional Tax,
 Provided funds, TDS from Contractor payment etc as per the applicable law
- Timely submission of statutory documentation with Govt. Department.
- Visit to Branch offices for review of systems and provide assistance

Short Term consultant (Accounts), 2008 UNICEF/Redr- Kolkata (West Bengal) For streamline of DIPECO project reporting system.

- Monitoring of fund utilization
- Partner's Monitoring Visit
- Preparation for audit work and submission of required documents by the auditors.

Short Term consultant (Accounts), 2007 Oxfam GB- Kolkata (West Bengal) Emergency Response Programme Flood Response Programme for Assam, Bihar, and Orissa

- Checking & scrutinizing staff claim; Medical, Leave, Leave Travel Allowance, (LTA)
- Check, verify Invoices of purchases, confirm and payments
- Data entry handle Income tax, Professional Tax, Provided funds, TDS
- Partner's Monitoring Visit.
- Audit work and submission of required documents by the auditors, Update knowledge on different laws, procedures etc.

Assistant (Finance and Administration) - 2001 - 2003 Oxfam GB, Jodhpur (Rajasthan) and Ahmedabad (Gujarat)

Checking & scrutinizing staff claim; Medical bills, Travel bills, Leave Travel Allowance, (LTA)
etc as per the organization rules and procedures.

- Check & Verify Invoices of purchases and take confirmation from concerned person or department for further action.
- Preparation Have vouchers Both Cash and Bank for Payment.
- Coding System for entry.
- Payments: -Clearance of outstanding payment to external parties and staff for their approved bills and advance for their official work.
- Statutory deduction from the bills/release of salary Via Income tax, Professional Tax, Provided funds, TDS from Contractor payment etc as per the applicable law.
- Sharing of information with superiors and inform them.
- Partner's Monitoring Visit
- Preparation for audit work via submission of required documents by the auditors.

Accountant with multiple roles in project management—1990-2001 Aga Khan Rural Support Programme (India) Ahmedabad Gujarat

- Budgeting for district office and its monitoring
- Fund management for branch and utilization as per sanction
- Field visits of the projects and its evaluation
- Training of the Staff and Village level institutions on:
 - a. Account keeping and credit management.
 - b. Village institute rules and regulations
- Checking & scrutinizing staff claim VIZ. Medical bills, Travel bills, Leave Travel Allowance, (LTA) etc as per the organization rules and procedures
- Check & Verify Invoices of purchases and take confirmation from concerned person or department for further action.
- Preparation Have vouchers Both Cash and Bank for Payment.
- Coding System for entry.
- Payments: -Clearance of outstanding payment to external parties and staff for their approved bills and advance for their official work.
- Statutory deduction from the bills/release of salary Via Income tax, Professional Tax, Provided funds, TDS from Contractor payment etc as per the applicable law.
- Timely submission of statutory documentation with Govt. Department.
- Banking Work: Preparation of cheque for withdrawal and party's Payments.
- Reconciliation work- Banks and Branch Offices.
- Preparation for audit work via submission of required documents by the auditors.
- Visit to Branch offices for review of systems and provide assistance
- Sharing of information with superiors and inform them.

Account Assistant, 1985-1990 Tarun Valves India Pvt Ltd- Ahmedabad-Gujarat

- Routine accounts
- Scrutiny and sanctioning of vouchers
- Preparation of financial reports on monthly basis
- Helping accountant in finalization work

Audit cum Accounts assistant, 1984-85 J.P. Shah & Co, (Chartered Accountant Firm) Ahmedabad- Gujarat

- Voucher auditing work
- Routine work

Apprentice Clerk, 1983-84 Ashoka Textile Miils (Lalbhai Group)-Ahmedabad-Gujarat

- Out-ward Inward Registration Department.
- Spinning department

Education

Qualification	Board University	Year of Passing	Grade	Subject
S.S.C	Gujarat Board	1977	2 nd	English, Maths, Science
H.S.C	Gujarat Board	1979	2 _{nd}	Accounts Secretarial Practice, Economics, English
B.COM	Gujarat University	1982	3rd	Accounts, Economics, English, Commercial communication, Statistics
LLB	Gujarat University	1985	2 nd	Taxation, Laws and Legislations

Additional Qualifications:

- Passed G.C.C Examination in 30 WPM in English Type writing.
- Computer Familiarity about various accounts packages like, Z-Plus, Z-Loader, EX, Telly, People Soft, imp rest, MS Word, Excel etc.
- Familiarity in self-correspondence, general office routine works.
- Passed Hindi Prathama & Prarambik Examination conducted by Rastriya Bhasa Prachar Board.

Seminars/workshops/on job trainings attended:

- Supported/Liaised for MP state agency in organizing conference on climate change at Bhopal and Ujjain in 2015-16 year
- Attended various training programme; Capacity building, Organizational Development, Gender sensitization, Financial management, Human resource management, Cohesion Foundation Trust at its head office and project offices, 2005-2013.
- Emergency Contingency Plan Exercise (ECP), Oxfam and Redr-India, 2011
- "Logistics in humanitarian operation training, Redr- India, Pune
- MNGO training of Trainers workshop, 2007

- Financial Management training, Oxfam GB, 2004
- Workshop on capacity building in budget analysis, SCF, Jaipur, 2004
- NGO Capacity Building training to enhance effectiveness and sustainability of Nongovernment organization, CORT, Baroda Gujarat, 2006
- Workshop on" Need Assessment in Emergency", Oxfam/Redr-India, 2008
- Attended "Disaster Risk Reduction" workshop, PCII and GIDM, 2012

Knowledge of Languages: English, Hindi, and Gujarati (Mother tongue)